Guide to the Paul Weinberg Photographs, 1979-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paul Weinberg photographs 1979-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Weinberg, Paul
15 linear feet Extent: 433 Items
South African born documentary photographer. Collection contains black and white and color prints from several of Weinberg's exhibits and books including Travelling Light, The Moving Spirit, In Search of the San, Going Home, Once We Were Hunters, Kosi Bay, Working the Land & Back to the Land, and Durban-Impressions of an African City. Photographs document rural indigenous communities and urban culture in several African countries. Also included are 10 CDR's containing high resolution scans of photographs in the collection. These disks have been removed from the collection migrated to the electronic records server.
RL.01358
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Paul Weinberg Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Biographical Note
South African born documentary photographer.
Collection Overview
Collection contains black and white and color prints from several of Weinberg's exhibits and books including Travelling Light, The Moving Spirit, In Search of the San, Going Home, Once We Were Hunters, Kosi Bay, Working the Land & Back to the Land, and Durban-Impressions of an African City. Photographs document rural indigenous communities and urban culture in several African countries. Also included are 10 CDR's containing high resolution scans of photographs in the collection. These disks have been removed from the collection migrated to the electronic records server.
Subject Headings
Weinberg, Paul; San (African people) -- Social conditions; San (African people) -- Pictorial works; Africa, Southern -- Religion -- Pictorial works; South Africa -- Religion -- Pictorial works; Africa, Southern -- Social life and customs; Africa, East -- Social life and customs; South Africa -- Pictorial works; Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2006-0119), 1979-2004
  Accession contains black and white and color prints from several of Weinberg's exhibits and books including Travelling Light, The Moving Spirit, In Search of the San, Going Home, Once We Were Hunters, Kosi Bay, Working the Land & Back to the Land, and Durban-Impressions of an African City. Photographs document rural indigenous communities and urban culture in several African countries. Also included are 10 CDR's containing high resolution scans of photographs in the collection. These disks have been removed from the collection migrated to the electronic records server.
  - Photographic Prints, 24 Boxes
    - Travelling Light, 1979-2004, Special Edition, (17x22, 13 b/w digital prints made on Hahnemuhle Inkjet Fine Art Paper (640267-501 Photo Rag 308 gm2)) (Box 1)
      A 25 year retrospective of Paul’s photography in Southern Africa.
    - Travelling Light, Special Edition, (17x22, 13 b/w digital prints) (Box 2)
    - Travelling Light, Special Edition, (17x22, 13 b/w digital prints) (Box 3)
    - Travelling Light, Special Edition, (17x22, 13 b/w digital prints) (Box 4)
    - Travelling Light, Special Edition, (17x22, 13 b/w digital prints) (Box 5)
    - Travelling Light, Special Edition, (17x22, 13 b/w digital prints) (Box 6)
    - Travelling Light, Special Edition, (17x22, 14 b/w digital prints)) (Box 7)
    - The Moving Spirit, (16 ½ x 23 ½, 18 b/w digital prints) (Box 8)
      Photographs of religious rituals and spiritual practices in Africa.
    - The Moving Spirit, (16 ½ x 23 ½, 18 b/w digital prints) (Box 9)
    - The Moving Spirit, (16 ½ x 23 ½, 20 b/w digital prints) (Box 10)
    - In Search of the San, 1984-1997, (12x16, 22 b/w silver prints) (Box 11)
      Photographs of Africa’s first people, the San.
    - In Search of the San, 1984-1997, (8x10, 20 b/w silver prints) (Box 12)
    - Going Home, 1984-1989, (8x10, 8 ¾ x 12 7/8, 18 b/w silver prints) (Box 13)
      Photographs of Pietermaritzburg, the neighborhood where Weinberg was raised
    - Going Home, 1984-1989, (8x10, 8 ¾ x 12 7/8, 16 b/w silver prints) (Box 14)
    - Going Home, 1984-1989, (8x10, 8 ¾ x 12 7/8, 17 b/w silver prints) (Box 15)
    - Once We Were Hunters, 1999, (10x15, 21 digital color prints) (Box 16)
      Photo and textual documentation of 7 different indigenous groups and their relationship to the land.
    - Once We Were Hunters, 1999, (10x15, 21 digital color prints) (Box 17)
    - The Culture of Cricket, Oct-Dec 2002, (12x16, 10 b/w silver prints) (Box 18)
      Depicts the culture of cricket in South Africa, urban to rural.
    - Khekhekhe Mtetwa-the story of a Zulu Family, 2000-2002, (12x16, 17 b/w silver prints.) (Box 18)
      Photographs of Khekhekhe Mtetwa, a famous sangoma (traditional healer) in Kwa Zulu Natal.
    - Kosi Bay, 1987-1995, (10 ½ x15 ¼, 11 ½ x15, 12x16, 20 b/w silver prints) (Box 19)
      A community of fishermen located on the Mozambique border of Kwa Zulu Natal. Work received the Mother Jones Documentary Award in 1983.
    - Kosi Bay, 1993, (10 ½ x15 ¼, 11 ½ x15, 12x16, 10 b/w silver prints) (Box 20)
    - Working the Land & Back to the Land, 1980s, (12x15 ¾, 10 b/w silver prints) (Box 20)
      Photographs made while working at the Environmental and Development Agency (EDA) as photographer and picture editor.
    - Working the Land & Back to the Land, 1980s, (12x15 ¾, 10 b/w silver prints) (Box 21)
    - Durban-Impressions of an African City, 1995-2002, (10x14 ¼, 16 dig. color prints) (Box 22)
    - Durban-Impressions of an African City, 1995-2002, (10x14 ¼, 17 dig. color prints) (Box 23)
    - An End to Waiting, 1994, (11 ¾ x16 ½, 20 b/w digital prints) (Box 24)
      Signed special edition, the first South African democratic election Feb-May 1994.
    - Poetry Africa, April 2003, (12x16, 10 b/w silver prints) (Box 24)
      Photographs of the annual Poetry Africa festival in Durban, South Africa.
  - Electronic Files, 10 CDR's
    - In Search of the San (Data-cd 001)
    - Travelling Light (Data-cd 001)
    - Once We Were Hunters - Mozambique and Namibia (Data-cd 002)
    - Once We Were Hunters - Bushmen - Namibia (Data-cd 003)
    - Once We Were Hunters - Kenya and Maputuland (Data-cd 004)
    - Once We Were Hunters - Kenya (Data-cd 005)
    - Once We Were Hunters - Zimbabwe and Richtersveld (Data-cd 006)
    - Impressions of an African City (Data-cd 007)
    - Elections (Data-cd 008)
    - The Moving Spirit - Part One (Data-cd 009)
    - The Moving Spirit - Part Two (Data-cd 010)